DURING THE JOSEON DYNASTY,
THE LARGE WATERWAY ACROSS HANYANG
WAS CALLED GYEONGGANG RIVER
THE MOST THRIVING AND BUSTLING DOCK
Hey, over here!
ALONG THE GYEONGGANG RIVER WAS MAPONARU
Come on! Come on!
WITH THE CONSTANT INFLUX
OF BOATS AND MERCHANTS,
MAPO DEVELOPED INTO A LARGE MARKETPLACE
Hurry up.
Yeah, right here. Just drop it, okay.
Come on, get another load.
THE DOCK WAS OVERFLOWING
WITH MERCHANTS AND LABORERS,
AND AMONG THEM WERE BANDITS
WHO OVERSAW AND CONTROLLED THE SCENE
Now, now!
I need 10 men, 10 men for salt!
Come on. Come on.
No, I'm here first.
- Hey...
Get going!
PEOPLE HAD TO PAY A TAX TO BANDITS
TO BE ALLOWED TO WORK.
- Pay your selection tax.
Take your pass.
Without the pass, you can't work!
Whoa! Whoa!
And make sure you grab a carrier.
Hurry up! Move it. Move it, move it!
If I see any of you slacking off,
I'm gonna break all of your legs
and make you crawl!
No, it's over there.
You put it over there.
Yeah, good. Now come on. We gotta go.
The Murky Stream
ONE. ROGUES
- Get in line.
- Next.
What are you looking at?
Pass first.
PASS: A SIGN TO DISTINGUISH THE LABORERS
So here's your wage. Your tax.
WAGE: MONEY OR ITEM GIVEN
IN RETURN FOR LABOR
Hey, stop fighting.
You'll get your turn. Okay.
- Next up.
- Good work out there.
- Next.
- Yeah.
I want more.
What now? What?
We only earn two doe of rice,
you take half of it back as tax.
The other half...
don't we at least deserve that?
Who are you to whine about anything?
- Huh?
- I need enough to eat.
How do you expect me to live on this?
Give me a full doe of rice.
As you promised.
You have all these complaints.
Go hit the drum and call.
See if you can call His Majesty here.
Hey!
Anyone else thinks
this rice here isn't enough, huh?
If you can't work, don't work.
Hey, go there. Take all his wages
and make sure he never comes back.
Listen carefully.
If I ever see your face over here again,
you're dead.
Go. Give me that and leave.
- Let it go!
- Huh?
You son of a bitch.
- You better back away. This isn't yours!
- Why aren't you restoring order?
Die!
Rogue. Huh?
Where do you think you are?
Get away!
I'll cut you open.
Huh?
- What's this?
- Try me!
Don't come any closer.
Don't! Stay away!
You out of your mind?
I swear...
- Hold him.
- Grab him! Grab him!
Let go!
Stomp on him, you rogues!
You keep pulling the same shit!
You bastard!
Ah... enough. Enough.
He'll die that way.
Huh? Eat all you want.
Are there any more complaints?
Or are we done here?
Peace reigns when all you commoners
learn how to keep your big mouth shut!
Next.
Hurry up now.
He's here.
Sit down.
Now...
Yoon goes first, let's see the taxes.
Yes, boss.
Hmm.
Mapo remains as peaceful as ever,
it seems.
That's good.
And tomorrow
we can all expect a sunny day.
Yes, boss.
Two pil of cotton, boss.
Look at you, Bang,
you've settled in quick.
It's all thanks to you.
This is silk, boss.
Dongmak, you little shit!
Got a handle on it now, huh?
Yes.
What is this?
Sorry to say, boss, Mudeok is quite short.
He only has half the tax here.
Uh, not quite. Uh...
Why do you have to say that?
It was that Officer Park prick,
he took a whole mal of rice...
and messed up our...
Shut up and pay your taxes
or else you're a traitor.
There's no reason to go there.
I was already gonna
get it all later.
- So it's...
- You can delay death,
but can't avoid taxes.
Oh, hey, don't tell me you're also
gonna weigh in on this.
You better offer up your clothes...
to make up for the missing tax.
That's the rule, no?
Are you suggesting I loosen the sash
and walk around naked like this?
I must say, my dear younger brother,
your wit truly has no equal.
Feeling shy?
Should I untie it for you, then?
Listen, kid...
you better cut it out.
It wouldn't be a good idea
to get on my nerves.
Let's be careful
with our words now.
You can stop.
You can stop trying to act tough in front
of the boys before you regret it.
You're an old man
who can't fight for shit.
Son of a bitch!
Watch your mouth or I'll...
You got a death wish?
Look here, huh?
You all know I've been a bandit so long
that my bones have hardened to steel.
Respect your elders.
- Boss.
- What is it?
At times like this,
it's custom to settle things
with a proper fight to restore order.
Our new recruits are all watching.
I hate to set a bad example.
Think of their discipline.
Mudeok.
Ah. Yes?
What do you make of this challenge?
Are you willing to fight him?
Oh, wait, Boss,
I wouldn't even think
of fighting a baby still wet
from the mother's womb.
- That wouldn't be fair.
- Sounds like you're scared.
What's wrong?
You said you had bones of steel.
Shit.
Come on, you piece of shit.
- How is this gonna turn out?
- Let's go.
Let's take this outside, huh?
Brother, is this really what you want?
You're a pathetic son of a bitch.
You're dead now!
You don't even know
how fucking dead you are.
Okay!
Now what are we waiting for?
Let's take this outside, asshole!
He's gonna show him.
Go.
Let's go!
Yeah, let's go!
Ha!
Let's make this quick.
Oh!
Hey. Hey.
Hey. Come on!
Kids are adults.
They don't listen...
until they've had a beating.
Hit him!
Get back here!
- Wait!
- Coward!
Stop!
Brother, come out here and fight.
Have it your way.
All right.
Are you out of your mind, Mudeok?
What's wrong with you?
Why don't you shut your mouth?
Did you forget already, huh?
If Deokgae stopped
the fight a minute later,
you'd be up there in heaven
right now with your ancestors.
Who was it that restored order
to Maponaru, damn it?
It was all thanks Deokgae and me,
the two of us.
Now those scavengers and insects
are trying to steal my spot.
You just watch.
I'll wipe the floor with Bang and Yoon.
Then I'll be the forefinger again.
Wow, what ambition you got?
Why would anyone wanna be
the forefinger instead of the thumb?
- You're crazy.
- Hey!
You gotta learn that men like us
will only go so far.
Chief State Councilor at best.
Huh? Going for the crown,
though, is treason.
I always knew your ambitions were small.
I didn't know they were this...
This fucking son of a bitch!
Hey, you! With the hat!
Damn it.
Come here. Come on over.
What was that?
You are nothing but a fool.
That piece of shit.
Did you see how scared he was?
Brother, wait.
Those people,
they don't look like they're from here.
You little shits.
None of you can fight.
None of you have any guts.
Weaklings, all of you.
Just get out of the fucking way!
No one's in your way, though.
I mean, you could...
Oh, right, Mudeok.
While we're out here,
let's find you something to wear.
If you show up shirtless again,
your wife's gonna beat you
to death tonight.
Who will beat their husband
like that, huh?
I'll throw her out in the streets.
Get out! You refuse to touch your wife
but you run around naked, huh?
Why don't you
take your clothes off for me?
How dare you hit your husband like that?
You'll regret this!
Get back here. You...
Forget the day job,
at least do your night job!
Everything's backwards here.
Get back here!
Fine, then! Run!
Oh, that man. Asshole!
♪ I can't go on ♪
♪ I can't live
with all my wife's nagging ♪
♪ To die, I am too young ♪
♪ To live, life is a mess ♪
♪ A mess ♪
Oh! You're here today, brother.
Oh...
What brings you all the way
here today, brother Bang?
Look at you, lounging around
without a care in the world.
Oh's guild needs 10 men to carry rice.
Oh. They told me
to put the salt first, though.
When the higher-ups
tell you to do something,
you better do it instead
of talking so much. Yeah?
Tell me you understand, huh?
Get it done.
Yeah, I got it. Okay. Thank you.
- Here.
- I'll take care of it.
You can count on me.
You rotten son of a bitch.
Have his manners gone into exile?
I'll start recruiting folks now.
He's dead to me.
I need 10 men to carry rice up.
All right?
You dropped something.
Gather up!
Two!
- 3!
- 4!
- 5!
- 7!
- Eight!
- Nine! And 10! The line ends here.
Hey, old man, no work for you.
Next time, all right?
- Come back next time.
- Everyone else, fuck off.
- Get out of here. Okay?
- Go, go, go.
- Get going!
- Okay.
We'll collect your selection charge.
Pay the tax!
Hurry. Pay the tax.
- Take your passes.
Pay your tax.
It's just a little bit.
Go ahead, the carriers are that way.
Pay your selection charge.
Here.
Here, take your pass.
Without the pass, you don't count.
Hey, Mudeok, what's going on here?
Now what's wrong?
This isn't the correct order.
The salt should be unloaded first.
I just do whatever I'm told to do.
When it comes to the order,
I have no say in that.
I docked my boat half a day ago.
How can you ignore that
and unload the rice before the salt?
Look, it's not me
that makes the decision, huh?
If you've got a problem,
go find the higher-ups
and ask them what to do.
Good grief.
That bastard, he's still showing
his face around here.
Shit.
Hey! You!
Damn it.
Here!
Hey, what did I tell you, huh?
You can't work here anymore.
Please allow me to work.
I will never complain
about the wage again.
Wait, are you crazy?
Yoon, we have to talk.
We docked three days ago,
I was pushed back again.
That's supposed to mean something?
Clouds are forming.
And? Stay patient and wait your turn.
If it starts to pour,
I could lose over half the salt.
Shut up, you idiot.
Look here, young man.
Mapo has always had certain customs.
We know
it's always been first in, first out.
Hey, look. Listen.
It's not like
I'm the one who makes the law.
We are not passing any laws. Right, boys?
I want to talk to your boss, then.
The esteemed Chief Kang
is gonna head up.
One more shot.
Lord Deokgae.
What do you mean by "lord"?
The real lord will be disappointed.
Hmm.
Would you move up my turn in line?
I'm carrying salt,
I'll be in trouble if it rains.
When rain's involved...
everyone's in a hurry.
Are they not?
Now that's a despicable tactic.
That covers the rush charge.
Can you please hurry?
Yoon, you hear that?
I hear you, Boss.
Chief Kang should be rushed ahead.
Got a rush order in for Choi's guild!
Much appreciated.
You take care now.
So you shift the order
and they pay a charge.
A rain charge for the rain.
A flood charge if there's a flood.
And the commoners'
blood and sweat,
you make sure to squeeze them dry.
Let's compare, then.
That's nothing.
A drop of piss in the Gyeonggang River.
An inspection charge for inspecting.
A training charge for training.
A charge for new assignments
and another charge for leaving.
The amount
that we're squeezed by our lords,
we don't have a drop of sweat left either.
Not a drop, huh?
Not a drop left, you say.
Not a drop.
I could tear you apart right now.
I show a bit of mercy
and he walks all over me.
Is that it?
No, I would never. My lord, I wasn't...
Then why do you speak when I'm speaking?
Come here.
Closer.
If you do not watch your tongue...
you could die.
Without a doubt, my lord.
Drink it.
Oh.
All right, yes, thank you.
What a fool. I was just joking.
You were so scared.
- Hey! Pour me a glass.
- Yes.
Of course, my lord. Yes.
Good evening, sir. Allow me to enter.
We finished. Everything's been unloaded.
You paid a rush charge, I heard.
I had to pay.
On top of everything else,
a rush charge.
Those thieving bastards.
Father.
The bandits are only petty thieves.
They're just someone else's tools.
The real issue is the officials
who sit around milking the rewards
of their corruption from the shadows.
What's this nonsense?
Have you been drinking?
We know the bandits
are reporting to someone.
Silence, you fool.
You should know when to stop.
We're only merchants.
Words like those will bring us trouble,
so we ought to be careful.
That's why...
That's why I need to become an official.
You can't be an official
if you don't even pass the exam.
You've been saying
you'd pass for 10 years now.
It's time you learned the trade.
That life isn't for me.
If one is born as a man,
it's his duty to rise to office
in order to rule the world.
Wouldn't you agree?
My one and only son, a rainbow chaser.
There's more, sir.
I checked the storage earlier.
A number of items from Ming
appear to be missing.
They're missing from the safe?
Who could have taken them?
Who else could it be?
SABYEOKHEON
These are precious.
So please accept my apologies in advance,
as I can't offer this opportunity
to everyone.
How precious could it be?
Considering you want two pil of silk,
let's have a look at it.
I'll be the judge.
As you're aware,
in Joseon, it's impossible to find
anything made of gold at the moment
since His Majesty had it prohibited
for being far too extravagant.
However...
this object was an offering
from a Ming envoy.
It could be yours.
- Isn't that exciting?
- Enough.
I will take it off your hands.
Yes.
Madam...
do you know Yu Rang of Qin?
He once spoke these immortal words.
"A meaningful man will lay down his life
for someone who sees who he is."
"Whether it's men or things,"
"they won't shine until they're met
with someone who sees their value."
That said,
who here would like to meet that value?
Oh, my goodness!
You look like a celestial maiden.
How beautiful.
They call it wagasa in Japan.
Look how beautiful it is.
Imagine you're out boating.
What better to give you shade
from the sun?
- Ten nyang!
- Five nyang more!
- Ten nyang more!
Lift it up! High!
Little brat.
I told you to get married,
not steal and sell someone's property.
I did not steal, we're family.
- And it was family property.
- Higher, you brat!
I got five pil of silk for it.
What?
It was worth two pil.
My profit was more than double.
You... You're telling me
you made five pil?
Father...
you know I want to be a merchant.
Right?
Please, Father.
A girl cannot learn the trade.
It's hard. Being a merchant
is nothing like dealing with ladies.
You may not realize, Father...
ladies can be as difficult
to sell to as men.
Ah, are you still at it?
I'll make my business silk
instead of salt and lumber.
Nice, pretty silk.
Raise it.
Lift the pot!
Assistant Officer Lee is here.
Start upstream, Ilsam.
YONGSANJIN
SEOGANGJIN
Ilsam of Seogang, my lord.
I hope everything has been going well.
Dochi of Yongsan. Pleasure, my lord.
YONGSANJIN
Deokgae of Mapo.
MAPOJIN
Here to pay respects.
Chadol of Dongho here.
DONGHOJIN
Jakdu of Nodeul. Allow me to bow.
NORYANGJIN
- Yes, yes.
Gaebong of Hangang River.
HANGANGJIN
-
Greetings, Gangseop of Dongjak.
DONGJAKJIN
You're gathered here today
for two reasons.
First, I want you to crack down
on nomads entering the capital.
Drive them off
before they dock at the port.
I won't hold any of you accountable...
should someone die.
Yes, my lord.
Inspection charge next.
Our coffers are empty.
The country's struggling financially.
However, exams are over
and new officials have been appointed.
We must celebrate.
So for the time being,
I'll double the inspection charge.
Understood?
Yes, understood.
- And Jakdu.
- Yes?
Your mother's 49th day since passing,
isn't it approaching?
Indeed, my lord.
I'll send saeu-jeot
and two quilted clothes.
- Just know that.
- You honor me deeply, my lord.
May you live long and prosper.
Right.
Stay focused
and tend to your duties.
It's Dochi, sir.
May I say a word, my lord?
Let's hear it, then.
Regarding Yanghwajin.
Smugglers who hail from outside
are starting to appear one by one
in our country.
I hear the court has been concerned
about it as well.
And the authorities,
they're not cracking down.
These rats roam about
with no consequences.
Fools like us...
we can't understand why that is.
And?
If you allow us, we can neatly
clean this entire mess.
We need to beat a few
to set an example.
It will not only strengthen
your position--
Enough!
I ought to fry those eyes of yours.
That would be a fitting reward
for this good deed.
What made you think this was a good idea?
To lecture your elders?
No, my lord. I would never dare to--
You think you have something to teach me?
And I was so generous.
Well, then, what were you saying?
What do you wish to do?
Huh?
My lord, I was only...
I beg your forgiveness!
You should just do as I say.
Who are you...
- to judge...
- My lord!
and decide anything?
Please spare me.
You just need to do as you're told!
I do the thinking!
Got that?
I'll say it again.
With everything in disarray,
I don't need your opinions.
Do as you're told and do it well.
My lord.
We dogs have been nothing but loyal.
Show us mercy.
Then just carry out your duties.
That fucking bastard!
- That ugly piece of shit lost his temper.
- I'm tired of this.
One of these days,
I'll stick a knife in his neck!
You'll see!
Hey, Jang's guild needs 12 men.
Good to see you, brother.
It's heavy cargo, all right?
So make sure to select the ones
with strong legs.
Hey, don't worry.
I'll take care of it, brother.
Who do you have here? It's Mudeok.
Mudeok? That's why we're worried!
He mouths off too much.
Fresh out of his mother's womb
yet he has no idea what respect is.
The selection begins now.
Twelve men to carry heavy cargo!
- Get out of my way.
- Get back in line.
- Count from the front.
- One.
- Two.
- Three.
- Four.
- Five.
- Six.
- Seven.
- Eight.
- Nine.
- Ten.
- Eleven.
- Twelve.
- Up to there.
Everybody else...
Hey! Wait, wait, wait, wait.
What's this geezer doing here?
Get rid of him.
Hey, young man!
Yeah, you, the fresh one. Get over here.
Hey, Beanpole, he means you.
Hey, wait!
How can you change the order?
It's my turn now.
Just take a look at how heavy
all that cargo is.
You're a mung beansprout.
- Too small and weak.
- Not fair.
I've been waiting here since dawn today.
Please let me work! Show me some mercy.
Aw, how diligent!
I haven't... I haven't eaten in two days.
I know I may look weak but I can do
the work of two or three.
So, please, please give me a chance.
Okay, sure. Hey, move it along.
Hey, if you have your pass, move.
- No!
- Shut up, already!
Stupid old man!
Come on, what do you think you can do?
Huh?
We're done.
When the boss tells you no,
you need to listen.
- You like living, right?
- Please.
I beg you, let me work today.
Otherwise my family will starve to death.
Please, give me the pass.
- What are you waiting for?
- Move him out of here.
- Let's go.
- What are you doing?
Get him back.
Hey, young man, you know me, don't you?
- Hey, hey, hey! Get him out of here.
- You know me.
- Tell them you won't--
- Grab him.
I beg you, tell them!
Please! Please talk to them!
Please, please!
Young man! Young man!
Let's go for a swim.
Okay, bye-bye!
You don't want to work?
Should I give it to someone else?
Go on!
Oh, shit.
His shoulder's like a rock.
Hey!
Come over here.
What the...
You little shit, wait a minute.
When an elder calls you,
you should bow and say,
"Thank you for your generosity."
I'm waiting.
Well?
- Thank you for your generosity.
- That's right.
Haven't seen you around here.
Whoa, look at that body!
What are you? Are you a runaway soldier?
No, sir, I'm not.
Are you on the run from the law?
Why are you asking me?
Well, you're not just some commoner.
Not when you've got sword scarring
like that.
Huh?
I got hurt while I was working.
I can tell you're lying.
Just by looking at the claws,
I can tell if it's a docile kitten
or a ferocious tiger.
I'd better get going.
To find more work.
Who said I was done talking?
I'm done.
Go on.
See you around!
- Hey, brother.
- Huh?
Who's that, a worker?
Was he causing trouble?
- Hey, Walwal.
- Yeah?
Find out where he lives.
- That man?
- Yeah.
- Yoon?
- Yes, boss?
What's the delay?
I'm guessing there's a lot to unload
because it's an envoy.
Ah, this is quite the turnout.
Move your asses!
Hey, these things are to be offered
to the king.
Be careful!
Oh, come on! Would you hurry up?
Huh, if I see any of you slacking off,
I'm gonna break all of your legs and make
you crawl the rest of the way.
- Out of the way.
- Ow!
What the hell?
Pass him up.
You fool.
Get your priorities straight.
Hurry up and get the luggage out.
- Now!
- The luggage?
Is wealth...
worth more than a man's life?
Do you really mean to ask me that?
People are like pebbles on a path.
Nothing's more worthless than human life.
How dare you?
You bastard.
Keep your eyes down.
You want to be dragged
to the Police Bureau?
I apologize.
Forgive me, sir.
You fool.
Don't you ever glare like that.
- Yes, sir.
- Go and fetch it now.
It's worth more than you.
Yes.
The King spoke.
The law's clear.
By unloading the minister's luggage,
you are working for the country
which means it's compulsory labor.
In other words,
that means there will be no pay.
- Keep that in mind.
- No pay?
Why do I hear murmuring while my brother's
out here talking?
Shut it! If you want to be selected, stay.
The rest of you leave. Scatter!
- Get out of here!
- Get moving!
If you're not paying us,
we should get fed.
We still get fed for compulsory labor.
- Those bastards.
- You there.
Come on up here. You're too far to hear.
It's the law. We all need to be fed.
What was that about the law?
Yeah, you heard him.
No matter if it's compulsory labor,
step right up if you're hungry.
Here's something to eat!
Huh?
No one?
Nobody wants to eat?
That's too bad for you.
This man might die
if no one steps forward.
Well?
He's bleeding pretty bad.
Okay, this is your last chance, huh?
Huh?
Hey, you.
What's that look in your eye?
No matter where you go, there's always
one loach that dirties the water.
Wow, you got some muscles on you.
Oh!
You're the man, huh?
What a man he is!
Stop looking at me like that.
Damn you.
I was gonna let all of you off easy.
But I've changed my mind!
Huh?
Look at you all having fun.
Assistant Officer Lee!
What brings you here?
I don't care where you're from
or where you're going.
If I ever see you again, you're dead.
The lot of you are no better than rogues.
He's an innocent man.
You dare beat him in broad daylight?
Hey, hey, all of you.
You're dismissed. Quickly.
Quickly. Take him away.
- Hurry! Scatter!
- Come on!
Didn't I tell you not to cause any scenes
and just stay quiet?
Did I or did I not, huh?
I'm no longer able to ignore
the amount of complaints I've received.
Your misconduct is well known.
Hey, hurry! Go fill up a mal with barley
and deliver it to his house.
Okay.
Right, fill it up all the way.
Keep going. Faster.
Do you know which bandit lives longest?
The one who can read my mind.
Oh, shit.
I still feel like I'm on pins and needles
every time I see his face.
I guess His Majesty is lucky that son of
a bitch is one of his officials.
Hey, hey!
Mix sand in with that.
Put two handfuls in there, huh?
When he eats, his teeth will fall out.
Spit on it, all of us.
Now, where's the sand?
Which one of you stole my rice, huh?
Was it you?
Sit down.
Why do you always think
I did it, huh?
Show me your rice bag now!
Then what? You can tell whose rice it is?
- Shit! Show me, damn it!
- Wait!
- Hey!
- You son of a bitch!
It's mine!
I told you...
No, no, no, no!
Sir, please, I beg you.
Let me work today.
Otherwise my family will starve to death.
Please, I beg of you.
I haven't... I haven't eaten in two days.
Are you in here, old man?
Hello?
Hurry up! A man is dead!
This way! Over here!
Hurry!
What's happened? He's dead.
He's dead!
How could this happen?
Don't fall.
Careful up there!
Get down.
Right there! There!
What a pleasant day to go boating.
The water was very calm.
It was, wasn't it?
I spent so much money
on this dress.
How dare you taint this
with your filthy hands?
We should go.
Don't you think so?
Sure.
Oh, boy.
We've finished unloading.
Good. Well done.
You can all go home now. Go on.
What? Wait a minute. Where's our pay?
Look at them there. You see over there?
They're not from just any noble families.
That's the Scholar-official's wife
and Second State Councilor's
daughter-in-law.
How can we go and ask them for the wage?
No pay for compulsory labor yesterday.
Now we can't get paid
because they're from noble families.
How are we to make a living?
I'll tell you how.
Have you lost your mind?
Why are you glaring like that?
Go, get lost.
I can't starve anymore.
Just pay us.
Damn you!
What are you, a cow?
Did everything I say bounce off
that thick skull of yours?
They didn't pay me either so why
are you whining at me?
Go! Get paid, then.
What's going on with all of you?
I keep seeing you idiots talking back
more and more these days.
I'll seriously brand you as traitors
if you don't watch your step.
Do you hear me?
Answer me.
Answer me!
Yes.
Return the passes and go now.
You'd better keep your mouth shut.
Leave now. Scatter!
Sons of bitches.
Fine.
But if I find out you've been lying to me,
I'll kill you myself.
What?
You...
Wait, where are you going?
That was awfully rude of you.
Are you the lady
I saw earlier at the port?
- You went boating.
- And?
Who paid today for the boat ride?
Was it one of you?
I was the one who paid.
Please pay us.
You owe us our wages.
Wages? What do you mean?
You got our labor so
someone has to pay for the work,
no matter how noble your family is.
No one should work for free.
That's not it, my lady.
We paid for everything up front.
As far as I was told, we paid for
both the boat and the laborers.
You heard her.
You're blocking the road?
They told me that they weren't paid.
You really think a Choi's guild noblewoman
would lie
just to save so little?
I'm sorry.
But no one received any pay.
Let us pass or you'll regret it.
Look what we have here.
Now you're really out of line.
My lady!
Tell the lady you're sorry. Go on.
No apology?
I haven't eaten in three days.
Brother, let's knock some sense
into him already.
I don't know what's going on.
All I know is, I wasn't paid for the work.
You haven't learned.
Nothing a good beating won't fix.
My lady, you should go.
Leave this fool to me.
- Be on your way.
- All right.
We should go.
Unless...
you'd like to witness
the death of this dog.
Don't just stand there.
Surround him.
Now that we ate,
let's work off a little sweat.
Know that I'm not a kind person.
That just makes it better.
We don't put up with rebels.
- All this for a doe of rice?
- Look at those eyes.
Oh, my, oh, my.
You bastard.
You got a real death wish, don't you?